I'm on the event reference page,
أتصفح الآن صفحة مرجع الحدث،
and this page lists out all of the different DOM events that can happen.
وتحتوي هذه الصفحة على قائمة بجميع أحداث DOM المختلفة التي يمكن أن تحدث.
And what's really cool is that if we scroll down a little bit,
وما هو رائع حقًا أنه إذا ممرنا إلى الأسفل قليلًا،
we can see that they are grouped by common category.
يمكننا أن نرى أنه يتم تجميعها حسب الفئة المشتركة.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
Let's scroll down a bit,
لنقم بالتمرير إلى أسفل قليلًا،
and we can get to the mouse events.
يمكننا أن نصل إلى أحداث الماوس.
So these are all of the mouse events on page.
حسنًا هذه جميع أحداث الماوس على الصفحة.
And look, here is the click event that we keep seeing,
انظروا، إليكم حدث النقر الذي نشاهده،
and here's the double click.
وإليكم النقرة المزدوجة.
And if we use the mouse wheel,
وإذا استخدمنا عجلة الماوس،
there's the wheel event. Scroll up a bit.
فهناك حدث العجلة. لنمرر إلى أعلى قليلًا.
We can see here are some keyboard events,
يمكننا أن نرى بعض أحداث لوحة المفاتيح،
pressing keys, letting keys up.
مثل الضغط على المفاتيح، وتحرير المفاتيح.
And let's just keep looking here.
لنتابع البحث هنا.
There are some other cool events.
هناك بعض الأحداث الرائعة الأخرى.
Here's the scroll event.
هذا حدث التمرير.
When you submit a form,
عندما ترسلون نموذج،
there are the form events,
توجد أحداث النموذج،
and here's the submit event when a form is submitted.
وهذا هو حدث الإرسال عند إرسال حدث.
It will fire the submit event that we can listen for and then respond to that.
سنقوم بإنشاء حدث الإرسال الذي يمكننا الاستماع إليه ثم نرد على ذلك.
Then there are some other CSS events here,
ثم هناك بعض أحداث CSS الأخرى هنا،
some for animation, some for transitions.
بعضها للرسوم المتحركة، وبعضها للعمليات الانتقالية.
This page has a ton of information,
تحتوي هذه الصفحة على الكثير من المعلومات،
and I definitely recommend you checking it out.
لذا أوصيكم بفحصها بالتأكيد.